Hi I'm Richard Fields and in this clip we are going to talk about how to buy a back packing sleeping bag.
There are two basic kinds of bags in terms of how they are built.
One is made with synthetic material and the other is made with down.
The down bag is lighter, warmer, but if you are going to be in any kind of wet climate or in any danger of getting that bag wet, wet down is useless and takes forever to dry.
The synthetic bag will continue to keep you warm even when wet although it is not as compressible and it is a little heavier.
Mummy bags, those are the form fitted bags have less air space in them and therefore will keep you warmer.
They are more restrictive but they tend to be warmer and lighter.
Things to consider of course is what kind of temperatures are you going to be encountering.
It is better to buy a bag that is a little too warm than one that is not warm enough.
An additional thing to consider is how tall you are.
You are certainly going to want to buy a bag that will completely cover your shoulders and over your head.
If you are a side sleeper it is not as critical if you tend to sleep on your back or your stomach then you definitely have to have a bag that is long enough for you.
When purchasing a sleeping bag it is to your advantage to go to a pro shop.
They can help you get the right bag and the right fit at the right temperature for you and that is how to buy a sleeping bag.